The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Twelfth Episode
The Prince and the Gypsy
I see Prince Sapphire is
coming! Good morning, Sapphire!
Good morning, Tink!
Hey!
Reckless! Were you
trying to kill yourself?!
What the hell is going on here?
Did you see that
you almost ran me over?
But he's the one who ran right at me!
If that's really the case, I
apologize for my friend's mistake.
What? So you already know each other!
Anyway, fortunately,
he didn't get hurt!
You think so?
It seems the opposite to me!
Ow, that hurts!
- Are you kidding?!
- Listen here, pretty boy!
How dare you? You hurt my
friend and you dare to laugh in his face?
You're going to get a lesson!
- No, not tickling! Stop it!
- Get him!
- But where did he go?
- Where did he disappear to?
- He was right there!
- Damn!
I'm here!
Wow, you're so strong!
Of course, because he
is the Prince of Silverland!
What?! A Prince should
be much more elegant.
I'll tell you, you don't seem
very well-dressed either.
Yes, but it doesn't matter to me.
I am a gypsy.
Gypsy? What is the characteristic
of a gypsy?
Gypsies are nomads.
My people are always on the move.
You know, to make a living,
we go around singing,
doing magic tricks
or stealing.
My name is Jin.
Are your parents
gypsies too?
Yes, they were,
but they died a long time ago.
I would love
to be a Prince too.
I would like to have
a palace all to myself.
Do you want to become
the master of a palace?
Are you making fun of
me? I don't have a penny!
How do I become
the owner of a palace?
And yet, for one day,
you will be able to have it.
What do you plan
to do, Sapphire?
- See?
- May I know what you want to do?
Hey! Like this, now,
he looks a lot like you!
I'm reading a book called
"The Prince and the Pauper".
Here it is! It's the story
of a Prince and a beggar...
...who switch roles.
A beautiful story!
I will make it a reality!
And since I now know a poor
boy, I will swap roles with him!
- Are you up for it, Jin?
- I want to see what will happen!
Geez! How long are they going to take
to change?
Darn! Dressed like that, I don't
recognize them! They look identical to me!
Now we will change our lives!
Do you agree, Jin?
Yes! I'm going to eat right away!
Wait! Where are you running?
Hey! Wait! Where are you running?
Finally free!
I'll be able to do whatever I want!
And no etiquette! Magnificent!
I'll be able to play all the time!
No more studying!
Who is that rude person
who knocked over my sign?!
But that's Tink!
Help, Sapphire!
Please, help me!
What's going on, Tink?
I've been kidnapped
by the street urchins!
Hey, you!
Are you by any chance friends with this flea?
Of course! You mustn't bully
the weak!
How dare you speak to me like that?
- Do you want me to teach you a lesson?
- Boss, make him fight!
Good idea! If you want to bring
this kid back,
- you'll have to beat me!
- Do I have to fight?
- Then come on! Bring it on!
- I'm going to have fun, rookie!
Aiuto!
Help!
- Help us!
- Come on! You can do it!
But it's not deep!
Help!
It's true, you can touch the bottom.
- We're even! Shall we do another
try? - Yes, I'm up for it too!
Look what I'm capable of!
- Did you see?
- And now look at me!
- Well done! Excellent!
- Really funny!
Hi! How is it going? Why aren't you answering?
Don't you know that I am the Prince?
You must respect me!
You must reply to my greeting
with the utmost deference!
It's empty...
To those maidens
I must look very funny.
Help, they want to kill me!
Sapphire, look at that beautiful sunset!
Yes, it's beautiful, but now I have to go
I'm coming with you, Sapphire! Wait!
Please,
could I have some water?
Ah, it's you, Jin! Thank
goodness you're back!
We thought you had left us!
Jin, I want to tell your fortune. Let's
see what destiny has in store for you.
So: one, five, eight.
I'll put this one here, this other
one here, then like this and then..
My dear Jin, your card is.
Here it is!
According to this card,
you're a girl?!
By now I've become
too old!
My magic doesn't work anymore!
Little brother, I'm glad
that you're back!
I saved some food for you!
Hey, where are you two going? Today he
didn't even earn a single cent,
so he is only entitled to
half a portion, if he wants it!
And if he doesn't want it, all the better!
Come on, Jin!
I realized that you are not Jin.
Who are you?
I am Jin's sister! I won't tell
anyone that you're not the real Jin,
but please,
tell me where he is now.
You know, Jin and I have
swapped roles.
Now he plays the Prince
instead of me.
Really? But that is magnificent!
Oh, here's Lizzie! Hello! You know, this
little sparrow is my best friend.
Every evening he returns to me.
What? Is it already evening?!
Good grief, how late it has gotten!
It will be dark soon
and Sapphire is still nowhere to be seen!
Oh, here's Jin!
Hello, Tink!
I had to do a lot of things
at the castle.
I'm dead tired!
My loyal followers, I will give you
what remains of the potion
...that can reveal
if Sapphire is male or female!
- Try not to fail this time!
- We put the liquid...
...on the tips of the swords,
so, if we touch a boy,
- he will turn blue!
- If we touch a girl, red!
If we touch a man, yellow!
Get ready to surround him!
Nylon's assassins!
What do you want? Don't you know
that I am the Prince?
Precisely! We were just
waiting for you, Your Highness.
Hit! Perfect!
Help!
He's running away! Chase him!
End of the line, Your Highness!
Don't worry,
it was just a joke!
That was only water!
Lift your face a little!
- Just water?
- But you're a boy!
Of course I'm a boy! Why?
What's strange about that?
Oh, no! But then..! Then..!
This way!
Jin must already be
waiting for me. Let's hurry!
Yes!
Alarm! Alarm!
Jin, you know you can't
leave here!
Go back to sleep immediately,
otherwise it'll be worse for you!
Nylon, repeat that once more.
It is so, Grand Duke: the Prince
turns out to be male!
Then there must be something
wrong with the potion!
That's not possible, Grand Duke!
I have tested that potion
several times...
..and it has always turned out to be
highly effective!
Damn it! If the Prince is
really a boy, I am ruined!
I can't believe it!
Nylon, come here!
- Yes, sir!
- The only thing left is to kill Sapphire!
It is not that simple
with that little devil, Grand Duke!
I can believe it! With those idiots
at your service!
That is why you must win
the trust of the gypsies!
Yes, I'm beginning to understand.
No, it's not what you think!
I had no intention of running away!
I only wanted to send the real Jin
back among you!
We exchanged clothes
to try a different life.
He was able to spend
a day in my castle,
because I am the Prince
of Silverland.
What the hell am I hearing?! Hey,
friends! Did you hear that too?
Jin has gone crazy!
It's true! I am a real Prince!
But you must believe me!
Please, Macigno,
forgive my brother!
He didn't do anything wrong!
Nothing wrong?! He wanted to sneak off
so he wouldn't have to work anymore!
On this,
the law of the gypsies is drastic:
no forgiveness!
I will work hard
and earn for him too!
If you promise to work
for him as well, then things change.
Come on, boys!
Cut Pepita's ropes!
You will go to the city to
sell this bundle of firewood.
Do I have to go to the city right away?
If you sell this bundle before
dawn, I will free your brother.
He won't be able to sell it!
How can he sell it at night?
If he fails to sell it,
you will be hanged.
Have faith, brother.
I will definitely sell it.
Good luck.
What could that be?
I'm too scared! The
forest is terrible at night!
I will never make it, my little brother!
It's the city!
Selling firewood!
Do you want firewood?
No, thank you!
Do you want to buy firewood?
I have a bundle of firewood!
My firewood!
Oh, what trouble!
I must try to get it back!
Help! Help! Help!
- Help me! I'm drowning!
- I hear screams!
Good heavens!
That girl is in danger of drowning!
- Help! Help!
- I will save her!
Give me your hand! Like this!
I won't make it on my own...!
Please, friend lightning,
give me a hand!
Thank you, friend!
I will always be grateful to you
Hey, you! Please, open your eyes!
Don't die!
I feel so cold!
Dad!
Mom!
Open your eyes, please!
Don't die! I helped you!
You must go on living!
Lord!
Please, Lord, save her!
I have never asked you for anything,
but now I beg you:
do me this favor!
Oh my!
How wonderful,
I saw my mother in a dream!
And what is this? It must be
a gift she gave me!
Thank you, mom!
I thank you, Lord.
Hey, Jin! Pepita hasn't returned!
If she doesn't come back before
dawn, I'll play a nasty trick on you!
I made it!
Well done, Pepita!
Look!
This is gold!
Look how it shines!
You can free Jin now, too!
- Pepita, I'm so happy!
- I'm happy too!
Excuse me! Macigno, I
have something to ask you!
Whatever you want! I
know your master pays well!
You will get a lot of
money, if you kill the Prince.
Damn it! Jin will get
caught in the middle!
The Prince, this morning, will
take a walk with Baron Nylon.
You will ambush him!
You will take care of it
yourself with four of your men!
A Prince should be worth
a tidy sum.
- Hey! Nick and Jaguar!
- Yes, boss!
- Cutty and Sal!
- Here we are!
Remember, boys,
we must not fail!
Good!
Good heavens, Jin is in danger!
Prince, please,
help my brother!
If Jin were to die,
I would die too!
My little Lizzie!
Don't worry, Pepita!
I will help your brother
and you'll see he won't die!
I hope so!
Like lightning!
A long morning walk
is a wonderful thing.
Don't you think, Prince? I am
honored to accompany you.
I already feel a bit tired. I would
prefer to return to the castle.
How about a nice race to
the castle, Your Highness?
But where is he going?
How distracted that Nylon is!
He went in the opposite direction.
Help!
Help, Prince! Help! Help!
Jin, I'm coming!
Just in time, Prince!
Thank goodness you arrived!
Damn it!
What does this brat want?
- Gypsies!
- Here we are!
- They are here!
- For all the devils in hell!
But that's Jin!
What are you doing here?
- Go back! Go!
- Sorry to disappoint you,
but I'm not going back at all!
Ah, is that so? Now you'll see!
Well done, Prince!
You're just as strong as I thought!
What happened to the assassins?
The end they deserved!
They're down there, over that way.
And tell me, did you like it
at the castle?
No, there is nothing interesting.
And what about you? Did you have fun?
Well, you know, "fun"
isn't the right word.
But I'm glad
to have been among the gypsies
I've learned a lot of things.
Really, Sapphire?
Anyway, it's time to say goodbye.
Pepita is waiting for you.
Of course!
But then the real Prince
was the fake Prince...
...and the one who was Prince
was not the Prince!
I don't understand anything anymore,
damn it!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP